主演: 湯姆·克魯斯
主演: 妮可·基嫚
製片兼導演: 史丹利·庫柏力克
片名: 《 大 開 眼 戒 》
（紐約市  聖誕節前夕）
親愛的  妳有看到我的皮夾嗎?
Honey, have you seen my wallet?
不是在床頭櫃上嗎?
Isn't it on the bedside table?
我們已經遲到了
Now listen, we're running a little late.
我知道
I know.
我看起來怎樣?
How do I look?
很完美
Perfect.
我的頭髮呢?
Is my hair okay?
很美
It's great.
你根本沒看
You're not even looking at it.
很漂亮
It's beautiful.
妳一向都很漂亮
You always look beautiful.
你給羅絲電話跟傳呼器號碼了嗎?
Did you give Roz the phone and pager numbers?
我放在冰箱上  走吧
Yeah, I put it on the fridge. Let's go.
馬上來
Coming.
好吧
All right.
我好了
I'm ready.
保姆叫什麼名字?
What's the babysitter's name?
羅絲
Roz.
好吧  羅絲  我們要走了
Okay, Roz, we're going now.
妳看起來真是美極了  哈福太太
You look amazing, Mrs. Harford.
謝謝
Thank you.
海蓮娜  妳要睡了嗎?
Helena, are you ready for bed?
是的  媽咪  我可以待晚一點看《胡桃鉗》嗎?
Yes, Mommy. Can I stay up and watch The Nutcracker?
- 幾點開始?  - 九點
- What time's it on? - 9:00.
- 好吧  - 我可以等到你們回來嗎?
- You can watch that. - Can I stay up until you get home?
- 不行  親愛的  - 那就太晚了
- No, darling. - It'll be a little late for that.
電話號碼在冰箱上...
The phone number is on the fridge...
裡面也有吃的  請自便
and there's food in there, so help yourself.
我們應該不會超過一點
We shouldn't be later than 1:00.
- 我會讓計程車載妳回去  - 謝謝  哈福醫生
- I'll hold our cab to take you home. - Thanks, Dr. Harford.
- 要乖乖聽話喔  寶貝  - 晚安  爹地  媽咪
- You be good, baby. - Good night, Daddy, Mommy.
- 晚安  甜心  - 早上見
- Good night, sweetheart. - See you in the morning.
- 維克特  艾羅娜  - 比爾  艾莉絲
- Victor, Illona. - Bill, Alice.
- 聖誕快樂  - 謝謝你們光臨
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you for coming.
- 謝謝你們光臨  - 我們怎麼可能錯過
- Thanks so much for coming. - We wouldn't miss it for the world.
艾莉絲  看看妳  真是明艷動人
Alice, look at you. God, you're absolutely stunning!
我不隨便對人這麼說  對吧?
I don't say that to all the women. Do I?
- 才不  他老是這麼說  - 真的?
- Yes, he does. - He does?
你還記得你幫我找的整骨師嗎  給我整手臂那位?
That osteopath you sent me to, the guy that worked on my arm?
- 我現在發球可厲害呢  - 他可是全紐約最棒的
- You ought to see my serve now. - He's the top man in New York.
從他給我的帳單就看得出來
I could have told you that, looking at his bill.
進去坐  喝杯酒  享受這派對
Go inside, have a drink, enjoy the party.
待會兒見  謝謝你們來
I'll see you in a little bit. Thanks for coming.
你有認識的人嗎?
Do you know anyone here?
一個也沒有
Not a soul.
你覺得紀格勒為什麼每年都邀請我們參加聖誕派對?
Why do you think Ziegler invites us to these things every year?
這就是出診的下場
This is what you get for making house calls.
那個彈鋼琴的傢伙  看到沒有?
You see that guy at the piano?
他是我醫學院同學
I went to medical school with him.
真的?
Really?
作為醫生  他蠻會彈琴的
He plays pretty good for a doctor.
他不是醫生  他輟學了
He's not a doctor. He dropped out.
各位先生女士  希望你們玩得愉快
Ladies and gentlemen, I hope you're enjoying yourselves.
樂團現在中場休息  我們十分鐘後回來
The band's gonna take a break. We'll be back in 10 minutes.
謝謝
Thank you.
我們過去打個招呼吧
Let's go over and say hello.
親愛的  我真的需要上個洗手間
I desperately need to go to the bathroom.
你去打招呼  我們約個地方見  吧台怎麼樣?
You go and say hello, and I'll meet you where? At the bar?
好
Good.
南丁格爾
Nightingale.
尼克·南丁格爾
Nick Nightingale!
我的天呐  比爾
Oh, my God! Bill.
比爾·哈福  你過得怎樣  兄弟?
Bill Harford! How the hell are you, buddy?
- 我們多久沒見了?  - 我不知道  十年了吧?
- How long has it been? - I don't know. 10 years?
不只吧
And a couple.
- 有時間喝一杯嗎?  - 當然
- Do you have time for a drink? - Sure.
你一點都沒變
You haven't changed a bit.
我該說謝謝嗎?  你過得怎樣?
Thanks, I think. So how you doing?
還不錯  你也知道  還可以
Not too bad, you know. Not too bad.
你變成鋼琴家了
I see you've become a pianist.
喔  我朋友都這麼叫我
Oh, yes. Well, my friends call me that.
你呢?  還是在當醫生嗎?
How about you? You still in the doctor business?
你也知道他們是怎麼說的  "一日為醫  終生為醫"
You know what they say, "Once a doctor, always a doctor."
沒錯  我的案例是  "從未行醫  終生非醫"
Yes, or in my case, "Never a doctor, never a doctor."
- 我一直搞不懂你為何輟學  - 是嗎?
- I never did understand why you walked away. - No?
輟學的感覺很棒  我常輟學
It's a nice feeling. I do it a lot.
乾杯
Cheers.
打擾一下  尼克  佔用你一點時間
Excuse me. Nick, I need you a minute.
馬上來
Be right with you.
我得去工作了  如果我們待會兒碰不到面...
I gotta go do something. If I don't catch you later...
我會在東村的奏鳴曲咖啡館表演兩個禮拜
I'll be down at the Village for two weeks at the Sonata Café.
- 如果有機會  過來看我  - 我會的
- Stop by if you get a chance. - I'll be there.
- 很高興見到你  - 我也是  老兄
- It's great seeing you. - Good seeing you too, man.
我想那是我的杯子
I think that's my glass.
我知道
Oh, I'm absolutely certain of it.
我叫桑德·薩沃特  我是匈牙利人
My name is Sandor Szavost. I'm Hungarian.
我叫艾莉絲·哈福
My name is Alice Harford.
我是美國人
I'm American.
很榮幸認識妳  艾莉絲
Delighted to meet you, Alice.
妳讀過拉丁詩人奧維德的《愛的藝術》嗎?
Did you ever read the Latin poet Ovid on The Art of Love?
他最後不是孤單一人...
Didn't he wind up all by himself...
把眼睛都哭瞎了...
crying his eyes out...
最後被流放到寒冷北方?
in some place with a very bad climate?
不過他之前過得很風流啊
But he also had a good time first.
非常風流
A very good time.
妳今晚跟誰來的  艾莉絲?
Are you here with anyone tonight, Alice?
跟我丈夫
With my husband.
喔  真可悲
Oh, how sad.
不過我想  他應該不介意我們共舞
But then I'm sure he's the sort of man who wouldn't mind if we danced.
妳是做什麼的  艾莉絲?
What do you do, Alice?
目前呢...
Well, at the moment...
我正在找工作
I'm looking for a job.
我曾經在蘇活區開畫廊
I used to manage an art gallery in SoHo.
不過倒閉了
But it went broke.
真可惜
What a shame.
我有幾個朋友在做藝術品買賣
I have some friends in the art game.
也許我可以幫上忙
Perhaps I can be of some help.
謝謝你
Thank you.
妳認識的人嗎?
Someone you know?
我的...
My...
丈夫
husband.
妳不認為婚姻最迷人的地方...
Don't you think one of the charms of marriage...
就是兩方都有欺瞞的必要嗎?
is that it makes deception a necessity for both parties?
妳是個美麗的女人...
May I ask why a beautiful woman...
可以擁有大廳裡任何一個男人  為何要結婚?
who could have any man in this room, wants to be married?
為什麼不呢?
Why wouldn't she?
有那麼糟糕嗎?
Is it as bad as that?
好得不得了
As good as that.
你認識諾拉·溫莎嗎?
Do you know Nuala Windsor?
不  很榮幸認識兩位
No, and it's very lovely to meet you both.
諾拉怎麼拼?
How do you spell Nuala?
NUALA
N-U-A-L-A.
你不記得我了  對不對?
You don't remember me, do you?
你曾經對我非常親切
You were very kind to me once.
曾經?  聽起來真是糟糕
Only once? That sounds like a terrible oversight!
我正在洛克菲勒中心拍照...
I was doing a photo session in Rockefeller Plaza...
那天正刮著大風?
on a very windy day...?
- 有東西跑進妳眼裡  - 第五大道上一半的東西
- And you got something in your eye. - Just about half of Fifth Avenue.
你真是位紳士  你把你的手帕給我...
You were such a gentleman! You gave me your handkerchief...
而且非常乾淨
which was also clean.
有時我就是這種英雄
Well, that is the kind of hero I can be sometimes.
妳知道從前女人為何結婚嗎?
You know why women used to get married, don't you?
何不由你來告訴我呢?
Why don't you tell me?
這是她們唯一能失去童貞的方法...
It was the only way they could lose their virginity...
然後才能夠跟其他男人做想做的事
and be free to do what they wanted with other men.
她們真正想要的男人
The ones they really wanted.
真有意思
Fascinating.
你知道醫生為什麼迷人嗎?
Do you know what's so nice about doctors?
其實不如外界想像得好
Usually a lot less than people imagine.
他們看起來總是...
They always seem so...
學識淵博
knowledgeable.
喔  非常學識淵博...
Oh, they are very knowledgeable...
在所有的事情上
about all sorts of things.
不過我想他們工作太認真了
But I bet they work too hard.
錯過了那麼多樂趣
Just think of all they miss.
妳說的可能沒錯
You're probably right.
女士們  我們到底要去哪兒?
Ladies, where exactly are we going?
說真的?
Exactly?
彩虹的盡頭
Where the rainbow ends.
彩虹的盡頭?
Where the rainbow ends?
難道你不想去彩虹的盡頭?
Don't you wanna go where the rainbow ends?
那要看在哪裡而定
Now that depends where that is.
讓我們一起去探索吧
Well, let's find out.
抱歉  女士們  哈福醫生  打擾一下
Excuse me, ladies. Sorry, Dr. Harford.
可以跟我來一下嗎?  紀格勒先生有事找你
Could you come with me for a moment? Something for Mr. Ziegler.
好吧
Fine.
待會兒再繼續?
To be continued?
來了
Yeah.
比爾  謝謝你過來
Bill, thanks for coming.
我們有點小意外
We had a little accident here.
怎麼了?
What happened?
她...
Well, she was...
她打了一針  就倒下去了
She was shooting up and she had a bad reaction.
她注射了什麼?
What did she take?
高速球還是雪球什麼的
A speedball or a snowball or whatever the hell they call it.
就是海洛英加古柯鹼
It's heroin and coke.
海洛英加古柯鹼?
Heroin and coke?
還有別的嗎?
Anything else?
我們還喝了幾杯香檳  就這樣了
We had a couple of drinks, some champagne. That was it.
她這樣有多久了?
How long has she been like this?
大概有五六分鐘吧  我想
Maybe five minutes, six minutes, something like that.
她叫什麼名字?
What's her name?
曼蒂  曼蒂
Mandy. Mandy.
曼蒂
Mandy.
曼蒂?
Mandy?
妳聽得到我嗎  曼蒂?
Can you hear me, Mandy?
妳聽得到我嗎?  如果妳聽得到我就搖搖頭
Can you hear me? Move your head if you can hear me.
如果妳聽得到我就搖搖頭  曼蒂  很好
Move your head if you can hear me, Mandy. There you go.
妳聽得到我
You can hear me.
妳可以睜開眼睛嗎?  曼蒂  妳辦得到嗎?
Can you open your eyes for me? Mandy, can you do that?
讓我看看妳的眼睛  很好  加油
Let me see you open your eyes. There you go, come on.
加油  看著我  看著我
Come on, look at me. Look at me.
看著我  看著我
Look at me. Look at me.
看著我  看著我  曼蒂
Look at me. Look at me, Mandy.
很好
Good.
我喜歡維克特收藏的藝術品  妳呢?
I love Victor's art collection, don't you?
對  非常棒
Yes. It's wonderful.
妳看過他的雕刻藝廊嗎?
Have you ever seen his sculpture gallery?
沒有
No.
我還沒看過
I haven't.
他的文藝復興時代青銅雕刻收藏很精采
He has a wonderful collection of Renaissance bronzes.
妳喜歡那個年代嗎?
Do you like the period?
喜歡
I do.
我也非常喜愛
I adore it.
雕刻藝廊就在樓上
The sculpture gallery is upstairs.
要不要上去看看?
Would you like to see it?
我可以帶妳去看
I can show it to you.
不會耽擱妳太久
We won't be gone long.
也許...
Maybe...
只是不是...
not just...
現在
now.
妳真是嚇壞我們了  小妞
That was really one hell of a scare you gave us, kiddo.
對不起
Sorry.
妳現在覺得如何  曼蒂?
How are you feeling now, Mandy?
好多了
Better.
妳是個非常非常幸運的女孩
You are a very, very lucky girl.
妳知道嗎?
You know that?
我知道
I know.
妳這次沒事
You're gonna be okay this time.
不過妳不能繼續這樣做
But you can't keep doing this.
懂嗎?
You understand?
明白
Yeah.
妳必須去戒毒所  妳知道吧?
You're gonna need some rehab. You know that, don't you?
我知道
I know.
那就好
Okay.
維克特...
Well, Victor...
這一切就交給你了
I'll leave the rest to you.
她可以穿上衣服離開了嗎?
Is it okay if I dress her and get her out of here?
不行  我會再觀察她一個小時
No, I'd keep her here for another hour.
再一個小時?
Another hour?
然後再派人帶她回家
Then I'd have someone take her home.
好的
Okay. Okay.
- 晚安  曼蒂  - 聽著...
- Good night, Mandy. - Listen...
今晚真是太感謝你了
I can't thank you enough for this.
- 你救了我的小命  - 幸好我在這兒
- You saved my ass. - I'm glad I was here.
比爾  我大概...
Bill, I probably...
我知道我不必多說...
I know I don't have to mention this...
你也知道這是我倆的祕密
but this is just between us, okay?
當然
Of course.
謝謝
Thanks.
我想我喝太多香檳了
I think I've had a little too much champagne.
我想我得走了  我要去找我丈夫
I think I have to go and find my husband now.
不過我想他一個人應該也沒問題
But I'm sure he'll be all right on his own a little longer.
沒錯...
Yes...
不過我呢?
but will I?
妳當然沒問題
Of course you will.
不  不  不
No. No, no, no.
我真的該走了  我得走了
I really have to go. I have to go.
妳知道妳不必走
You don't, you know.
是的  我知道
Yes, I do.
艾莉絲...
Alice.
我一定要再見到妳
I must see you again.
- 那是不可能的  - 為什麼?
- That's impossible. - Why?
因為...
Because...
我結婚了
I'm married.
早安  麗莎
Good morning, Lisa.
早安  醫生  你的郵件
Good morning, doctor. Your mail.
很好  請珍妮爾幫我倒咖啡進來
Good. Please ask Janelle to bring me my coffee.
- 沒問題  - 謝謝
- Sure. - Thank you.
- 早安  莎拉  - 早安  醫生
- Good morning, Sarah. - Good morning, doctor.
"聖誕夜那晚  整棟房子非常寧靜...
"'Twas the night before Christmas, when all through the house...
一點聲音都沒有  連老鼠都沒出聲"
not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse."
好了  沒問題  妳可以穿上衣服了
Okay. That's fine. You can put your gown on.
幫媽咪拿著
Hold this for Mommy.
- 很期待聖誕節吧?  - 對
- Looking forward to Christmas? - Yeah.
- 會痛嗎?  - 會
- Does this hurt? - Yeah.
- 這裡嗎?  - 對
- Right there? - Yeah.
爹地一定會喜歡
Daddy's gonna like that.
選得好
Very good choice.
"在我...
"--before me...
跳進床裡"
when I jump into my bed."
我們該打電話給紀格勒家
謝謝他們邀請我們參加昨晚的派對
We should call the Zieglers and thank them for the party last night.
我已經打過了
I've taken care of that.
很好
Good.
要不要幫我把剩下的禮物包裝好?
So how do you feel about wrapping the rest of the presents?
明天再包  好嗎?
Let's do that tomorrow.
（OK繃）[ 卷大麻煙 ]
告訴我
Tell me something.
那兩個女孩...
Those two girls...
昨晚在派對上的那兩個...
at the party last night...
你...
Did you...
是否...
by any chance...
有機會...
happen to...
上她們?
fuck them?
什麼?
What?
妳在說什麼啊?
What are you talking about?
我說的是那兩個...
I'm talking about the two girls...
你哈得不得了的女孩
that you were so blatantly hitting on.
我對她們沒有興趣
I wasn't hitting on anybody.
她們是誰?
Who were they?
只是兩個模特兒
They were just a couple of models.
還有你為什麼跟她們一起消失這麼久?
And where did you disappear to with them for so long?
等等
Wait a minute.
我沒有跟誰一起消失
I didn't disappear with anybody.
紀格勒身體不舒服...
Ziegler wasn't feeling too well...
我被叫上樓去看他
and I got called upstairs to see him.
那妳自己又在跟誰跳舞?
Anyway, who was the guy you were dancing with?
紀格勒夫婦的朋友
A friend of the Zieglers.
他想要什麼?
What did he want?
去樓上...
Sex...
做愛
upstairs.
當時當地
Then and there.
就這樣?
Is that all?
對  就這樣
Yeah, that was all.
只是想要上我老婆
Just wanted to fuck my wife.
沒錯
That's right.
我可以理解
Well, I guess that's understandable.
可以理解?
Understandable?
因為妳是個...
Because you are a very...
非常美麗的女人
very beautiful woman.
等等
Wait. So...
只因為我是個美麗的女人...
because I'm a beautiful woman...
所以男人願意跟我說話...
the only reason any man ever wants to talk to me...
只是因為他想上我  你是這個意思?
is because he wants to fuck me. Is that what you're saying?
我想事情不像妳說的那麼簡單...
Well, I don't think it's quite that black and white...
不過我們都知道男人是什麼德行
but I think we both know what men are like.
所以基本上...
So on that basis...
我也可以假設你想搞那兩個模特兒
I should conclude that you wanted to fuck those two models.
我是例外
There are exceptions.
為什麼你是例外?
And what makes you an exception?
我是例外  因為...
What makes me an exception is that...
我剛好很愛妳
I happen to be in love with you.
因為我們已經結婚了...
And because we're married...
而且我絕不會對妳說謊...
and because I would never lie to you...
或傷害妳
or hurt you.
所以你的意思是...
Do you realize that what you're saying...
你不上那兩個模特兒的原因...
is that the only reason you wouldn't fuck those models...
是為了我著想?
is out of consideration for me?
而不是因為你不想
Not because you really wouldn't want to.
放輕鬆  艾莉絲
Let's just relax, Alice.
大麻讓妳容易激動
This pot is making you aggressive.
不  不是大麻  是你
No! It's not the pot. It's you!
你為什麼就不能給我一個直接的答案呢?
Why can't you ever give me a straight fucking answer?
我以為我給的就是直接答案啊
I was under the impression that's what I was doing.
我已經搞不清楚我們在吵什麼了
I don't even know what we're arguing about here.
我不是在吵架
I'm not arguing.
我只是想知道你話裡的涵意
I'm just trying to find out where you're coming from.
我話裡的涵意?
Where I'm coming from?
假設...
Let's say--
假設來說好了  有個大美女...
Let's say, for example, you have some gorgeous woman...
裸體站在你辦公室裡...
standing in your office naked...
你正在摸她的乳房
and you're feeling her fucking tits.
我想知道的是...
Now, what I wanna know...
我想知道當你抓著乳房時  你在想什麼
I wanna know what you're thinking about when you're squeezing them.
艾莉絲  我是個醫生
Alice, I happen to be a doctor.
這非常公事化...
It's all very impersonal...
而且旁邊一定有護士
and you know there's always a nurse present.
你是說  當你摸她的乳房時  你想的只有你的專業態度?
So when you're feeling tits, it's nothing more than your professionalism?
沒錯
Exactly.
當我幫病人看診時  我絕對不會想到性
Sex is the last thing on my mind when I'm with a patient.
那當她的小乳頭被你擠弄時...
Now, when she is having her little titties squeezed...
難道你不認為她可能正幻想著...
do you think she ever has fantasies...
英俊比爾醫生的小弟弟長什麼樣嗎?
about what handsome Dr. Bill's dickie might be like?
拜託  我可以向妳保證  這個他媽的虛構女病人...
Come on, I can assure you sex is the last thing...
心裡想的絕對不可能是性
on this fucking hypothetical woman patient's mind.
你為什麼這麼肯定?
And what makes you so sure?
如果沒有其他原因...
If for no better reason...
她可能只是害怕我將要告訴她的診斷
because she's afraid of what I might find.
好吧
Okay, okay.
那當你告訴她一切都沒事以後  接下來呢?
So after you tell her that everything's fine, what then?
接下來怎樣?
What then?
我不知道  艾莉絲...
I don't know, Alice...
接下來怎樣?
What then?
聽著
Look,
女人不會...
women don't...
女人基本上不會有那種想法
They basically just don't think like that.
百萬年的進化  是嗎?
Millions of years of evolution, right?
是嗎?
Right?
男人就得到處找洞插...
Men have to stick it every place they can...
而女人呢  只關心安全跟承諾...
but for women, it is just about security and commitment...
還有其他什麼鬼的
and whatever the fuck else!
有點過於簡化  艾莉絲  不過大概就是那樣
A little oversimplified, Alice. But yes, something like that.
你們男人真是搞不懂
If you men only knew.
我知道妳只是頭腦發昏  想要跟我吵架...
What I do know is you got stoned, you tried to pick a fight...
而現在妳又想讓我嫉妒
and now you're trying to make me jealous.
不過你不是會嫉妒的類型  對吧?
But you're not the jealous type, are you?
沒錯  我不是
No, I'm not.
你從來不會為我感到嫉妒  對吧?
You've never been jealous about me, have you?
沒錯  從來沒有
No, I haven't.
那你為什麼從沒為我感到嫉妒過?
And why haven't you ever been jealous about me?
我不知道  艾莉絲  也許因為妳是我老婆
Well, I don't know, Alice. Maybe because you're my wife.
也許因為妳是我孩子的母親...
Maybe because you're the mother of my child...
我知道妳絕不會對我不忠
and I know you would never be unfaithful to me.
你對你自己真是有信心啊...
You are very, very sure of yourself...
不是嗎?
aren't you?
不
No.
我是對妳有信心
I'm sure of you.
妳覺得很好笑嗎?
Do you think that's funny?
好吧  去他的
All right. Fuck it.
現在我們開始笑了嗎?
Now we get the fucking laughing fit, right?
你...
Do you...?
你還記得去年夏天在鱈角嗎?
Do you remember last summer at Cape Cod?
記得
Yes.
你還記得有天晚上在餐廳...
Do you remember one night in the dining room...
有個年輕的海軍軍官...
there was this young naval officer...
他跟其他兩位軍官坐在我們隔壁桌?
and he was sitting near our table with two other officers?
不記得
No.
服務生給他捎來一張紙條  他就離開了
The waiter brought him a message, at which point he left.
完全沒印象嗎?
Nothing rings a bell?
沒有
No.
嗯...
Well...
我那天早上在大廳第一次見到他
I first saw him that morning in the lobby.
他剛要登記進旅館...
He was checking into the hotel...
他跟著拉著行李的門僮...
and he was following the bellboy with his luggage...
走向電梯
to the elevator.
他看了我一眼  然後走過去  只是一眼
He glanced at me as he walked past. Just a glance.
就這樣
Nothing more.
但我幾乎...
But I could hardly...
動彈不得
move.
那天下午...
That afternoon...
女兒海蓮娜跟她的朋友去看電影...
Helena went to the movies with her friend...
而你跟我則在做愛
and you and I made love.
我們為未來做了計畫...
And we made plans about our future...
還談到了女兒海蓮娜
and we talked about Helena.
不過...
And yet...
我從頭到尾...
at no time...
想的只有...
was he ever...
他
out of my mind.
我想如果他要我...
And I thought if he wanted me...
即使只是...
even if it was only...
一夜情...
for one night...
我也願意放棄一切
I was ready to give up everything:
你
You...
海蓮娜
Helena...
我他媽的未來
my whole fucking future.
一切
Everything.
實在很奇怪  因為在那個時候...
And yet it was weird, because at the same time...
對我來說  沒有什麼比你來得重要
you were dearer to me than ever.
在當時  我對你的愛...
And at that moment, my love for you...
是既溫柔...
was both...
又悲傷
tender and sad.
我當晚幾乎睡不著...
I barely slept that night...
我第二天早上醒來  感到驚恐
and I woke up the next morning in a panic.
我不知道我是擔心他已經離開...
I didn't know whether I was afraid that he had left...
還是擔心他還在那兒
or that he might still be there.
但到了晚餐時間...
But by dinner...
我才知道他已經走了...
I realized he was gone...
我感到...
and I was...
鬆了一口氣
relieved.
喂?
Hello.
是  我是哈福醫生
Yes, this is Dr. Harford.
什麼時候發生的?
When did it happen?
不  不用了
No, no.
我知道地址
I have the address.
謝謝
Thank you.
路·耐森剛剛去世
Lou Nathanson just died.
我得去一趟  露個面
I think I have to go over there and show my face.
- 妳好  羅莎  - 晚上好  哈福醫生
- Hello, Rosa. - Good evening, Dr. Harford.
- 耐森小姐怎麼樣?  - 不太好  她在臥室裡
- How is Miss Nathanson? - Not so good. She's in the bedroom.
謝謝
Thank you.
請進
Come in.
瑪莉安...
Marion...
哈福醫生...
Oh, Dr. Harford...
你能來真好
How good of you to come.
我一聽到消息就趕來了
I came as soon as I got the message.
- 謝謝  - 我...
- Thank you. - I'm so...
- 我很遺憾  - 謝謝
- I'm so sorry. - Thank you.
妳的父親...
Your father was...
他是個勇敢的人
He was a very brave man.
喔  謝謝你
Oh, thank you.
妳還好嗎?
How are you holding up?
我有點麻痺
I'm a bit numb.
我想我還不能接受
I don't think it's really sunk in yet.
你要不要先坐下?
Would you like to sit down?
感覺很不真實
It's so unreal.
爹地今天過得很好
Daddy had such a good day.
他神智清醒  記得很多事
His mind was clear, and he remembered so many things.
然後他吃了一點晚餐...
Then he had a little dinner...
說他想睡一下
and he said he felt like taking a nap.
我進廚房跟羅莎說了不到半小時的話...
I went into the kitchen and talked to Rosa for half an hour at most...
當我走進來時  他已經...
and when I went to see how he was...
我以為他只是睡著了
I just thought he was asleep.
然後我...
Then I...
然後我才發現  他呼吸已經停了
Then I realized he wasn't breathing.
瑪莉安...
Marion,
從妳告訴我的過程...
from what you've said...
我相信妳父親是在睡眠中安詳過世的
I'm sure your father died peacefully in his sleep.
天呐  我希望是
Oh, God, I hope so.
我想我擔心他去世的方式...
I think I've been more afraid of the way it was going to happen...
遠超過擔心他去世
than his death itself.
妳打電話給其他親戚了嗎?
Have you had a chance to phone any of your relatives?
我試著打給我在倫敦的繼母  不過她不在
I tried to call my stepmother in London, but she was out.
我男朋友卡爾  已經幫我連絡了一些人...
My boyfriend, Carl, is making some calls...
他很快就會過來
and he'll be coming over soon.
我想你見過卡爾幾次
I think you've met Carl here a few times.
是的  我記得  他是老師  對吧?
Yes, I remember him. He's a teacher, isn't he?
數學教授
A math professor.
我們即將在五月結婚
We're going to get married in May.
那真是好消息  恭喜
Well, that's wonderful news. Congratulations.
謝謝你
Thank you.
卡爾收到密西根大學的聘書
Carl has a new teaching appointment at the University of Michigan.
我們很快就會搬過去
We'll be moving out there soon.
密西根是很美麗的地方  我想妳一定會喜歡
Michigan's a beautiful state. I think you'll like it a lot.
是嗎?
Yeah.
這對妳可能是很棒的改變  瑪莉安
It really could be a wonderful change for you, Marion.
我的天  不...
Oh, my God, no...
我愛你
I love you.
我愛你  我愛你  我愛你
I love you, I love you, I love you.
我不想跟卡爾走
I don't want to go away with Carl.
瑪莉安  我想妳不知道...
Marion, I don't think you realize--
我懂
I do.
即使我再也見不到你  至少我也要離你近一點
Even if I'm never to see you again, I want at least to live near you.
瑪莉安  聽我說...
Marion, listen to me. Listen to me.
妳太傷心了  不知道自己在說什麼
You're very upset right now, and I don't think you realize what you're saying.
我愛你
I love you.
我們根本不熟
We barely know each other.
我們的對話內容僅限於妳父親的健康
We haven't had a single conversation about anything except your father.
我愛你
I love you.
那大概是卡爾
That's probably Carl.
請不要輕視我
Please don't despise me.
- 妳好  羅莎  - 你好  湯瑪士先生
- Hello, Rosa. - Hello, Mr. Thomas.
- 她在臥室裡嗎?  - 對
- Is she in the bedroom? - Yes, she is.
謝謝
Thank you.
請進
Come in.
親愛的
Darling.
我非常遺憾
I'm so very sorry.
妳還好吧?
Are you all right?
我很好
I'm okay.
- 哈福醫生  晚上好  - 晚上好  卡爾
- Dr. Harford, good evening. - Good evening, Carl.
謝謝你今晚趕過來這兒
Thank you very much for coming over here tonight.
- 這是我應該做的  - 對我們來說意義重大
- It's the least I could do. - It means a lot to us.
謝謝
Thank you.
嗯  我剛好...
Well, I was...
其實我剛好要離開
Well, I was actually on my way out.
瑪莉安...
Marion...
妳父親非常以妳為傲...
your father was very proud of you...
我知道妳在最後幾個月給他帶來非常大的安慰
and I know you gave him great comfort these last months.
- 謝謝  - 謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
- 那麼...  - 那麼...
- Well... - Well...
我送你出去
I'll show you out.
晚安
Good night.
聽好了  她嘴裡含著一朵紅玫瑰
Listen to this. She had a red rose in her mouth.
就纏著我開始跳起墨西哥艷舞
She was doing a Mexican lap dance right in my face.
我是說真的  我脖子後面還有疤痕呢
I'm serious! I got scars on the back of my neck.
這個兩頭跑的傢伙是哪一隊的啊?
What team's this switch hitter playing for?
- 應該是粉紅基佬隊  - 看看這玻璃
- Looks like the pink team. - Look at this faggot!
小心點  玻璃
Hey, watch it, you faggot!
聖誕快樂  瑪莉亞
Merry Christmas, Mary!
- 你那些戳屁股的兄弟在後面  - 上好的肉  寶貝
- Your butt-brothers are back there! - Prime cut of meat, baby!
想鑽進來這巧克力隧道  對吧?  笨玻璃
You wanna take a ride in this fudge-tunnel, you stupid faggot?
你應該要有胸部的  你站那麼近
You should have tits, you're standing so close!
- 我的屎都比你大  - 來啊  男子漢
- I got dumps that are bigger than you! - Come on, macho man!
- 想打架嗎  寶貝?  - 只出不進  蜜糖
- You want a piece of this, baby? - Exit only, honey.
滾回你的基佬之城舊金山去
Go back to San Francisco where you belong, man!
不好意思  你知道現在幾點嗎?
Excuse me. Do you know what time it is?
十二點十分
Ten past 12.
有什麼特別計畫嗎?
Going anywhere special?
不  我只是在散步
No, I'm just taking a walk.
要不要找點樂子?
How'd you like to have a little fun?
什麼?
I'm sorry?
找點樂子?
Have a little fun?
（旅館）
我就住在這裡
I just live right down there.
要不要跟我進去?
Would you like to come inside with me?
跟妳進去?
Come inside with you?
對
Yeah.
在裡面總比外面好
It's a lot nicer in there than it is out here.
妳...
You...
妳住在這兒?
You live in there?
對
Yes.
一個人住?
By yourself?
不  我有個室友  不過她不在家
No. I have a roommate, but she's not home.
不會有事的
Hey, it's okay.
沒有人會打擾我們
Listen, no one will bother us.
沒關係  進來吧
It's okay. Come on.
來吧
Come on.
就是這兒
This is it.
樹還不錯
That's a nice tree.
抱歉有點亂  女傭今天休息
Sorry about the mess. Maid's day off.
這裡很...
It's...
舒適...
cozy. It's a...
很舒適的地方
cozy place.
還好啦
It's okay.
那麼...
So...
我們應該先談價錢吧?
Do you suppose we should talk about money?
也對
Yeah, I guess so.
要看你想做什麼而定
That depends on what you wanna do.
你想做什麼?
What do you wanna do?
妳推薦什麼?
Well, what do you recommend?
我推薦什麼?
What do I recommend?
嗯...
Well...
我寧願不要說出來
I'd rather not put it into words.
讓我幫你決定  怎麼樣?
How about you just leave it up to me?
- 我是妳的人了  - 好吧
- I'm in your hands. - Okay.
一百五怎樣?
And how does 150 sound?
非常好
Sounds wonderful.
別擔心  我不計時
Don't worry. I don't keep track of the time.
謝謝
Thank you.
請用  請用
Prego, prego.
- 謝謝  - 不客氣
- Grazie. - You're welcome.
如果我是義大利人  他就會用義大利文回答我
If I was Italian, he'd have answered me in Italian.
那麼...
So...
可以開始了嗎?
shall we?
抱歉
Excuse me.
喂?
Hello.
喂
Hi.
一切都還好吧?
Hi. Is everything all right?
還好  我只是...
Yeah. I was...
我只是在想  你還要在那邊待多久?
I was just wondering if you were gonna be much longer.
我現在不方便說話
Listen, it's a little difficult to talk right now.
大概還要一點時間
It could be a while.
你知道要多久嗎?
Any idea how long?
不  我不知道
No, I don't really know.
我們還在等其他親戚到
We're still waiting for some relatives to arrive.
那我要去睡了
Well, I'm gonna go to bed now.
好的  再見
Okay. Bye-bye.
那是比爾醫生太太?
Was that Mrs. Dr. Bill?
是的
Yes. Yes.
你得走了嗎?
Do you have to go?
我得走了嗎?
Do I have to go?
我想是的
I think I do.
你確定?
Are you sure?
恐怕是的
Yes, I'm afraid so.
不過我還是想付妳錢
But listen, I wanna pay you anyway.
妳之前說多少?  一百五?
How much did you say it was? Hundred and fifty?
對
Yeah.
不過說真的  不必麻煩了
But you know what? You don't have to bother about that.
不  沒關係
No, it's all right.
- 不  真的  你真的不必  - 不  我堅持
- No, really. You don't have to. - No, I want to.
- 真的?  - 真的
- Really? - Really.
非常感謝你
Well, thank you very much.
（奏鳴曲咖啡館）
（奏鳴曲爵士樂）
（尼克·南丁格爾）
謝謝
Thank you.
先生  晚上好  您要桌子還是吧台的位子?
Good evening. Would you like a table or would you like to sit at the bar?
- 桌子  - 請跟我來
- I'd like a table. - Please follow me.
- 您的外套?  - 謝謝
- Can I take your coat? - Thank you.
您要喝點什麼?
Could I get you anything to drink?
- 啤酒  - 馬上來
- I'd like a beer. - Certainly.
（奏鳴曲爵士樂）
一  二  一  二  三  四
One, two, one-two-three-four.
今晚到此結束  各位先生女士
That's it for tonight, ladies and gentlemen.
低音大提琴  賴瑞·麥維  鼓手  吉普·弗來明
On the bass, Mr. Larry McVey. On the drums, Kip Fleming.
吉他  獨一無二的巴比·伯曼
And on the guitar, the one, the only, Mr. Bobby Berman.
我們會在這兒表演兩週  請務必再度光臨
We'll be here for the next two weeks, so please do stop by.
我是尼克·南丁格爾  晚安
I'm Nick Nightingale. Good night.
- 尼克  真是太棒了  - 謝謝
- Nick, that was great. - Thanks.
- 南丁格爾  - 比爾  你來了
- Nightingale. - Hey, Bill, you made it.
不好意思  我來的時候  你剛好要結束
I'm sorry, I got here just as you were finishing your last set.
沒關係  反正今天樂團表現很差
That's all right. The band sucked tonight anyway.
- 您要喝什麼?  - 伏特加湯尼  謝謝
- What are you drinking? - A vodka and tonic, please.
謝謝
Thank you.
現在是什麼風把你吹來的?
So what brings you out at this hour?
- 我剛好有個病人在附近  - 你住在東村?
- I have a patient in the neighborhood. - You live in the Village?
不  我的公寓在中央公園西區
No, we have an apartment on Central Park West.
你結婚了嗎?
You're married?
九年
Nine years.
- 有小孩嗎?  - 有個七歲的女兒
- Any kids? - Yes, we have a 7-year-old daughter.
你呢?
How about you?
我有個老婆跟四個男孩  住在西雅圖
I've got a wife and four boys in Seattle.
你離家很遠呐
You're a long way from home.
人總得跟著工作跑
Well, you gotta go where the work is.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 這是你的樂團?  - 不  臨時拼湊的
- So is this your band? - No, it's a pick-up band.
- 你都跟誰表演?  - 任何人  任何地點
- Who do you normally play with? - Anybody, anywhere.
我今晚還有表演
I got another gig later tonight.
你今晚還要去別的地方?
You're playing somewhere else tonight?
他們大約兩點才開始
They only get started around 2.
在東村?
In the Village?
信不信由你  我根本還不知道地址
Believe it or not, I don't actually know the address yet.
你不知道?
You don't?
不  聽來也許荒謬  不過每次都在不同的地方...
No. It may sound ridiculous, but it's in a different place every time...
而且之前我都只待一個小時左右
and I only get it an hour or so before.
- 每次都是不同的地方?  - 目前為止
- A different place every time? - So far.
為什麼這麼神祕?
What's the big mystery?
老兄  我只是個鋼琴手
Hey, man, I just play the piano.
尼克  抱歉  是不是有什麼事我沒聽懂?
Nick, I'm sorry. Is there something I'm missing here?
我矇著眼睛彈
I play blindfolded.
- 什麼?  - 對
- What? - Yeah.
我矇著眼睛彈
I play blindfolded.
你在賣關子
You're putting me on.
不  我是說真的
No, it's the truth.
上次的矇眼布綁得不夠緊
And the last time, the blindfold wasn't on so well.
老天
Oh, man.
比爾  我這輩子看過的怪事不少...
Bill, I have seen one or two things in my life...
不過我從來...
but never...
沒看過這種事...
never anything like this...
也沒看過那麼棒的女人
and never such women.
好吧
Well...
抱歉
Excuse me.
喂?
Hello.
是的  先生  我是尼克
Yes, sir. Yes, sir, this is Nick.
我知道那在哪裡
I know where that is.
好
Right.
（費德里歐）
好的
Okay.
我現在馬上趕去
Well, I'm on my way right now.
好的  謝謝  再見
Okay, sir. Thank you. Bye-bye.
（費德里歐）
這是什麼?
What is this?
這是貝多芬的歌劇  對吧?
It's the name of a Beethoven opera, isn't it?
尼克
Nick.
這是暗語
It's the password.
暗語?
The password?
我很抱歉  必須把你丟在這兒  比爾
Yeah. Look, I'm really sorry to do this to you, Bill.
我真的得走了...
I gotta get going. I gotta go.
尼克
Nick...
你知道我絕不可能...
you know there is no way on earth...
就這樣讓你走  帶我跟你去
that you are going to leave here without taking me with you.
- 拜託  饒了我吧  - 尼克  聽我說
- Come on, buddy, give me a break. - Nick, I'll tell you what.
既然我已經有了暗語
I've already got the password.
給我地址就好  我自己去...
Just give me the address. I'll go there by myself...
我們之間完全沒有關聯
and there won't be any connection between us whatsoever.
聽著  即使我願意...
Listen, let's just say for one second...
假設我願意
that I was prepared to do that.
你穿的衣服也不可能讓你進得去
You couldn't get in anyway in those clothes.
為什麼?
Why not?
因為所有人都穿戴著戲服跟面具
Because everyone is always costumed and masked.
你怎麼可能在這種時候租得到戲服跟面具?
Where the hell are you gonna get a costume at this hour?
謝謝  零錢不必找了
Thanks. Keep the change.
（彩虹）
（戲服出租 / 晚禮服出租）
喂?  誰啊?
Yes? Who is it?
彼得  我是比爾·哈福
Peter, this is Bill Harford.
很抱歉在半夜把你吵醒  但是我需要你的幫助
I apologize for disturbing you at this late hour, but I need your help.
你要找誰?
Who is it that you want?
呃...
I...
很抱歉  我要找彼得·葛列寧...
I'm very sorry. I'm looking for Peter Grenning...
彩虹時尚店的老闆
the owner of Rainbow Fashions.
你叫什麼名字?
What's your name?
我是比爾·哈福
My name is Bill Harford.
我是葛列寧先生的醫生
I'm Mr. Grenning's doctor.
- 葛列寧的醫生?  - 對
- You are Grenning's doctor? - Yes.
好吧
Okay.
請等一下
Just a moment.
你要找彼得·葛列寧?
You are looking for Peter Grenning?
對
Yes, I am.
他一年前就搬到芝加哥了
He moved to Chicago over a year ago.
他搬去芝加哥了?
He moved to Chicago?
我完全不知道
I wasn't aware of that.
那你是彩虹時尚店的現任老闆囉?
Then are you the present owner of Rainbow Fashions?
對
Yes, I am.
首先...
Well, first of all...
容我再次向你致歉  在半夜把你吵醒  您是...
please let me apologize again for disturbing you at this hour, Mr...
米里區
Milich.
米里區先生  不過我真的是哈福醫生...
Mr. Milich. Just to let you know that I really am Dr. Harford...
這是我的紐約州行醫執照
this is my New York State Medical Board card.
好吧  你真的是哈福醫生
Okay, so you are Dr. Harford.
如果我看見彼得  我會告訴他你在找他
If I see Peter, I tell him you were looking for him.
喔  不  請等一下...
Oh, no, wait. Please, please...
我今晚來此的原因是...
Listen, the reason that I came here tonight was...
其實我需要一套戲服
Basically, the reason is that I need a costume.
我願意比一般租價多付你一百塊...
And I'd be happy to pay you $100 over the rental price...
算是補償帶給你的不便
for the inconvenience.
- 一百塊?  - 是的
- A hundred dollars? - Yes.
我想不了
I don't think so.
那麼...
Okay.
兩百塊呢?
How about $200?
比租價多兩百塊?
Two hundred dollars over the rental price?
對
Yes.
好
Okay.
進來吧
Come in.
世風日下  我得小心
Can't be too careful these days.
請進
Please.
你要找什麼樣的特殊戲服?
Is it any special costume you are looking for?
對
Yes.
我需要晚禮服  帶帽的斗蓬跟面具
I need a tux, a cloak with a hood and a mask.
帶帽的斗蓬跟面具?
A cloak with a hood and a mask?
- 對  - 好...
- Yes. - Okay,
我想我們應該有
I think we'll find something for you.
請跟我來
Follow me, please.
很好
Good.
- 看起來跟活人一樣  對吧?  - 對
- Looks like alive, huh? - Yes.
- 太棒了  - 來吧
- It's wonderful. - Come.
你要什麼顏色的斗篷?
So what color cloak?
紅色  咖啡色  紅色?
Red, brown, red?
黑色
Black.
當醫生的難道不想要色彩豐富一點的斗篷嗎?
The good doctor wouldn't like something more colorful?
- 我想不了  - 小丑  警察  海盜?
- I don't think so. - Clowns, officers, pirates?
不  我只要晚禮服跟黑斗篷...
No, just the tux, the black cloak--
帶帽跟面具
With a hood and a mask.
- 對  - 好
- Yes. - Okay.
你的外套?
May I take your coat?
- 你是看病的醫生  對吧?  - 對
- You are medicine doctor, yes? - Yes, I am.
- 我頭髮有一些問題  - 你的頭髮?
- I have some problem with my hair. - Your hair?
我最近掉髮很嚴重
It's starting to fall down too fast.
我兩個禮拜就掉了一大堆  大部分在這裡
I lost, in two weeks, a lot of hair. Mostly here.
- 你看看  在這裡  - 喔  在腦頂後面
- Look at this. Here. - Oh, here is.
- 看到沒?  - 看到了
- You see? - Yes.
然後呢?
And?
我想這恐怕不是我的領域
I'm afraid this really isn't my field.
什麼?  你幫不了我?
What? You can't help me?
你應該要找髮理學家  看頭髮的專科醫生
No. You should see a trichologist. It's a hair specialist.
米里區先生  說真的  現在時間已經很晚了
Mr. Milich, I've obviously left things a bit late tonight.
- 如果你不介意...  - 我也在趕時間啊  趕回去睡覺
- So if you don't mind-- - Okay, okay. I'm in hurry too, to get back to bed.
我了解
I understand.
黑斗篷  是吧?
So black cloak?
你有聽見什麼聲音嗎?
Did you hear something?
嗯
Mm.
那是什麼?
What is this?
（彩虹）
在搞什麼?
What is it?
What is this?
這裡到底發生了什麼鬼事?
What on earth is going on here?!
米里區  讓我解釋
Milich, I can explain everything.
妳  妳在這裡做什麼?
You! What are you doing here?
我一定要殺了妳
I promise I'll kill you!
還有你  難道你完全沒有羞恥心嗎?
And you! Have you no sense of decency?
兩位  難道你們完全沒有羞恥心嗎?
Gentlemen, have you no sense of decency?!
米里區  你瘋了嗎?
Milich, are you crazy?
是這位年輕小姐請我們來的
We were invited here by the young lady.
年輕小姐?  那是我女兒
Young lady? This is my daughter!
難道你看不出來她只是個孩子?
Couldn't you see she's a child?
- 你最好去跟警察解釋  - 警察?
- You will have to explain to police! - To the police?!
妳這小賤貨  我要殺了妳
You little whore! I kill you for this.
我發誓我會殺了妳
I promise, I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
請幫我把那小女孩抓住
Hold on to that girl for me, please!
米里區  豈有此理
Milich, this is preposterous.
這位年輕小姐邀請我們來的
The young lady invited us here.
你們看不出來她已經瘋了嗎
Couldn't you see she is deranged?!
醫生  很抱歉讓你久等
Doctor, I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
各位  這已經是警察的事了
Gentlemen, this is now a police matter.
請在此等候  直到我回來
You will please stay here until I return.
讓我們出去
Let us out of here!
那是不可能的
That's out of the question.
醫生  不好意思  你說你要什麼顏色的?
Doctor, sorry, what color did you say?
- 黑色?  - 黑色
- Black? - Black.
兩位  請有點禮貌  好嗎?  安靜下來
Gentlemen, please have the goodness to be quiet for the moment!
難道沒看到我在招呼客人?
Couldn't you see I try to serve my customer?
對不起
Sorry.
還有妳  小賤貨  馬上去睡覺  邪惡的東西
And you, little whore, go to bed at once, you depraved creature.
等我招呼好這位先生  我就來好好地修理妳
I'll deal with you ater I serve this gentleman.
你應該穿鑲白鼬皮邊的斗篷
You should have a cloak lined with ermine.
（佳節愉快）
好  一共是七十四塊半
Okay, that's $74.50.
七十四塊半  好吧
Seventy-four fifty. All right.
這是八十塊
There's 80.
我答應多給你五十塊  對吧?
I promised you 50 bucks over the meter, right?
如果你等我  我就給你一百塊
I'll make that a hundred, if you wait for me.
讓計價表繼續跑
Just let the meter run.
我給你另一半鈔票  再加上計價錶的錢
I'll give you the other half plus the meter when I get back.
- 怎樣?  - 你會去多久?
- Okay? - How long you gonna be?
我不知道  也許一小時  也許十分鐘
I don't know, maybe an hour or more. But maybe only 10 minutes.
我把我的東西留在這兒
I'll leave my stuff here in the back.
- 好嗎?  - 好吧
- Okay? - Okay.
晚上好  先生
Good evening, sir.
晚上好
Good evening.
有什麼我能為您效勞的嗎?
Can we be of any help?
我想你要的是暗語
I suppose you'd like the password.
是的  先生
If you'd like, sir.
費德里歐
Fidelio.
謝謝您  先生  我們會帶路
Thank you, sir. We'll run you up to the house.
晚上好  先生
Good evening, sir.
晚上好
Good evening.
暗語是?
Password, sir?
費德里歐
Fidelio.
謝謝
Thank you, sir.
我不知道你以為你在幹什麼
I'm not sure what you think you're doing.
不過你不屬於這兒
But you don't belong here.
很抱歉  不過我想妳認錯人了
I'm sorry, but I think you've mistaken me for someone else.
拜託  別傻了
Please! Don't be foolish.
你必須立刻離開
You must go now.
妳是誰?
Who are you?
我是誰不重要
It doesn't matter who I am.
你現在非常危險
You are in great danger.
趁現在還有機會快點走
You must get away while there's still a chance.
抱歉  能不能麻煩您讓我們單獨談談?
Would you be so good as to excuse us for a moment?
你玩得開心嗎?
Have you been enjoying yourself?
我到處看看  覺得很有趣
Well, I've had a very interesting look around.
你想跟我去一個更私密的地方嗎?
Do you wanna go somewhere a little more private?
私密?
Private?
也許是個好主意
That might be a good idea.
你在這裡啊  我到處在找你
Oh, here you are. I've been looking all over for you.
我可以把他借走幾分鐘嗎?
May I borrow him for just a few minutes?
我保證馬上帶他回來
I promise to bring him right back.
我想你不知道自己現在多危險
I don't think you realize the danger you're in now.
你騙不了他們多久的
You can't fool them for much longer.
你得在一切都太遲之前趕快離開
You've got to get away before it's too late.
妳為什麼要告訴我這些?
Why are you telling me this?
這不重要
It doesn't matter.
妳是誰?
Who are you?
你不需要知道  不過你得走了  快
You don't want to know. But you must go. Now!
妳能跟我來嗎?
Will you come with me?
不可能
That's impossible.
為什麼?
Why?
因為這會賠上我的生命  可能還有你的
Because it could cost me my life and possibly yours.
- 讓我看妳的臉  - 不行
- Let me see your face. - No!
快走
Go!
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
在外面等的計程車是您的嗎?
Are you the gentleman with the taxi waiting for him?
是的
Yes.
您的司機正在門口  急須跟您說話
Your driver's at the front door and would urgently like a word with you.
請向前來
Please, come forward.
請告訴我們暗語  好嗎?
May I have the password, please?
費德里歐
Fidelio.
沒錯  那是暗語...
That's right, sir. That is the password...
大門專用的
for admittance.
不過  您知道房子的暗語是什麼嗎?
But may I ask, what is the password for the house?
房子的暗語?
The password for the house?
是的
Yes.
很抱歉  我...
I'm sorry, I...
我好像...
I seem to have...
忘記了
forgotten it.
真是不巧
That's unfortunate.
因為在這裡  不論是忘記...
Because here, it doesn't matter whether you have forgotten it...
或根本不知道
or if you never knew it.
都必須卸下面具
You will kindly remove your mask.
現在...
Now...
請卸下衣物
get undressed.
卸下衣物?
Get undressed?
脫下你的衣服
Remove your clothes.
各位...
Gentlemen, please...
脫下你的衣服
Remove your clothes.
還是你要我們幫你脫?
Or would you like us to do it for you?
住手
Stop!
讓他走
Let him go.
讓我來
Take me!
我願意替他贖罪
I am ready to redeem him.
妳願意替他贖罪?
You are ready to redeem him?
是的
Yes.
妳知道如果這麼做...
Are you sure you understand what you're taking upon yourself...
妳會被怎麼處置嗎?
in doing this?
知道
Yes.
非常好
Very well.
你可以走了
You are free.
不過我警告你...
But I warn you...
如果你再繼續調查...
if you make any further inquiries...
或跟任何人提到...
or if you say a single word to anyone...
你今晚所見到的...
about what you have seen...
你跟你家人的下場...
there will be the most dire consequences for you...
將慘不忍睹
and your family.
你了解嗎?
Do you understand?
那女人會被如何處置?
What is gonna happen to that woman?
沒有人能改變她的命運
No one can change her fate now.
在這裡立下的承諾...
When a promise has been made here...
絕不可能改變
there is no turning back.
快走
Go!
（海蓮娜）
艾莉絲
Alice.
沒事了  沒事了
It's okay. It's okay.
對不起
I'm sorry.
對不起把妳吵醒  我以為妳在做惡夢
I'm sorry I woke you up, but I thought you were having a nightmare.
天呐
Oh, God.
我做了一個可怕的夢
I just had such a horrible dream.
現在幾點了?
What time is it?
剛過四點
It's a little after 4.
- 你剛到家?  - 對
- Did you just get home? - Yes.
比我預期的還要久
It took longer than I thought.
你一定累壞了
You must be exhausted.
來  躺下來吧
Come on, lie down. Lie down.
妳夢到什麼?
What were you dreaming?
就是一些...
It's Just...
一些詭異的事
Just these weird things.
什麼事?
What was it?
感覺好詭異
It was so weird.
告訴我
Tell me.
我們...
We were...
我們在一座荒廢的城市裡...
We were in a deserted city...
我們的衣服都不見了
and our clothes were gone.
我們裸著身體...
We were naked...
我好害怕...
and I was terrified...
而且我...
and I...
我又覺得羞恥
and I felt ashamed.
天呐...
Oh, God...
我好生氣  因為我覺得那是你的錯
And I was angry because I thought it was your fault.
你跑去幫我們找衣服
You rushed away to go find clothes for us.
你一不見  情況就不一樣了
As soon as you were gone, it was completely different.
我覺得好舒暢
I felt wonderful.
然後我躺在一座美麗的花園裡...
Then I was lying in a beautiful garden...
全身赤裸伸展在陽光下...
stretched out naked in the sunlight...
一個男人從樹林中走出來
and a man walked out of the woods.
就是我跟你說過的  在旅館遇見的男人
He was the man from the hotel, the one I told you about.
海軍軍官
The naval officer.
他看著我...
He stared at me...
然後大笑
and then he just laughed.
他嘲笑我
He just laughed at me.
不過還沒結束...
But that's not the end...
對吧?
is it?
還沒結束
No.
為什麼不告訴我後來的情節?
Why don't you tell me the rest of it?
那...
It's...
太恐怖了
It's too awful.
那只是一個夢
It's only a dream.
他吻著我...
He was kissing me...
然後我們開始做愛
and then we were making love.
我們身邊有好多人...
Then there were all these other people around us...
上百個人  到處都是
hundreds of them, everywhere.
大家都在亂搞
Everyone was fucking.
然後我...
And then I...
我開始搞其他男人
I was fucking other men.
好多人...
So many...
我不知道有多少
I don't know how many I was with.
你看見我躺在這些男人的臂彎裡...
And I knew you could see me in the arms of all these men...
操這些男人
just fucking all these men.
而我...
And I...
我想嘲笑你...
I wanted to make fun of you...
在你面前大笑
to laugh in your face.
我盡全力笑你
And so I laughed as loud as I could.
那大概就是你叫醒我的時候
That must have been when you woke me up.
（奏鳴曲咖啡館）
該死
Shit!
（吉斯比斯咖啡館  二十四小時營業）
- 你好  - 妳好
- Hi. - Hi.
一杯咖啡  謝謝
I'll just have a cup of coffee, please.
還要什麼嗎?
Anything else?
不了  謝謝
No, thank you.
不好意思
Excuse me.
妳知道隔壁的奏鳴曲咖啡館何時開門嗎?
Do you know when they get in next door at the Sonata Café?
- 我想通常兩三點會有人在辦公室  - 兩三點...
- I think there's usually someone in the office around 2 or 3. - 2 or 3.
我猜妳大概不認識尼克·南丁格爾吧?
I don't suppose, by any chance, you know Nick Nightingale?
他目前在那兒演奏鋼琴
He's playing piano over there right now.
尼克·南丁格爾?
Nick Nightingale?
當然  他常來這兒
Sure, he comes in here.
也許妳可以幫上忙...
Look, maybe you can help me...
因為我必須跟他聯絡上
because it's important that I get in touch with him.
妳知道他住在哪兒嗎?
Do you know where he's staying?
嗯...
Well...
我想我不應該隨便把他的地址給人
I don't know if he'd want me to give out his address.
沒關係  我是醫生
It's okay, I'm a doctor.
我其實是他的老朋友
I'm actually a very old friend of his.
呃  醫生...
Well, doctor...
他今晚有演出  你不能等嗎?
he'll be playing there tonight. Can't it wait until then?
聽著
Listen,
說實話...
to be perfectly honest...
是跟病情有關
it's a medical matter.
檢驗結果  我想他會希望能趕快知道
Some tests. I know he'll wanna know about them as soon as possible.
（旅館）
抱歉
Excuse me.
有什麼我能效勞的嗎?
Hi! How can I help you?
可以幫我接通尼克·南丁格爾先生的房間嗎?
Can you please ring Mr. Nightingale's room for me? Nick Nightingale.
很抱歉  南丁格爾先生已經退房了
I'm sorry, sir, Mr. Nightingale has already checked out.
- 他退房了?  - 是的
- He checked out? - Yes.
- 他有留下地址嗎?  - 恐怕沒有
- Did he leave a forwarding address? - No, I'm afraid not.
他何時退房的?
When did he check out?
大概今晨五點
About 5:00 this morning.
- 五點?  - 對
- 5:00? - Yes.
不會太早了嗎?
That's an early checkout, isn't it?
是有點早  沒錯
It is a little on the early side, yeah.
那麼...
Look...
當他走時  你有沒有注意到...
did you notice anything...
不知道...
I don't know...
什麼不尋常的地方?
unusual about him when he left?
不尋常?
Unusual?
- 你該不會是條子吧?  - 不
- Hey, you're not Five-O, are you? - No.
不  我是他朋友
No, I'm an old friend of his.
真的?
Really?
我是個醫生
I'm a doctor.
- 可以叫你比爾嗎?  - 當然
- Well, Bill...? - Sure.
你問這問題真是有趣  比爾...
It's funny you should ask that question, Bill...
因為南丁格爾先生離開時...
because actually there was something a little strange...
的確有些不尋常
about the way Mr. Nightingale left.
真的嗎?  發生了什麼事?
Really? What was that?
他大約在今晨四點半進來...
He came in this morning, about 4:30 a. m...
跟兩個男人
with two men.
非常壯碩
Big guys.
他們穿著體面  談吐得體
They were very well-dressed and very well-spoken.
不過你絕對不會想招惹他們...
But they weren't the kind of people you'd fool around with...
你知道我意思吧
if you know what I mean.
然後...
Anyways...
我注意到南丁格爾先生臉上有塊淤青
I noticed Mr. Nightingale had a bruise on his cheek.
說實話  我覺得他看起來有點害怕
To be perfectly honest, I also thought he looked a little scared.
害怕?
Scared?
對  對
Yes. Yes.
他說他要退房
He said he wanted to check out.
然後他跟其中一個男人上樓去
And then he went upstairs to his room with one of the men.
另一個男人留在大廳  幫他結帳
The other guy stayed down in the lobby and settled his bill.
當他們回來時  南丁格爾先生想塞給我一封信
When they came back, Mr. Nightingale tried to pass me an envelope.
不過被發現後  他們拿走了...
But they saw it and took it...
說如果有任何他的郵件或訊息...
and said that any mail or messages for him...
都會有經過授權的人來幫他收件
would be collected by someone properly authorized to do so.
然後他就被帶進車裡了
And then they just took him off in a car.
你知道他們去哪裡嗎?
Do you have any idea where they went?
不  完全不知道
No, not a clue.
既然如此...
Well, anyway...
非常感謝你的幫助
I certainly appreciate your help.
樂意之至  比爾
Anytime, Bill. Bye.
（彩虹時尚店）
- 啊  好醫生  - 米里區先生
- Oh, the good doctor! - Mr. Milich.
- 你的裝扮有成功嗎?  - 很成功  謝謝
- Was your outfit a success? - Yes, it was. Thank you.
很好
Good, good.
晚禮服  斗篷  鞋子
Tuxedo. Cloak. Shoes.
我想你忘記面具了
I think you forgot the mask.
- 不在裡面嗎?  - 沒有
- It's not there? - No, no, no.
也許你忘在派對上了?
Maybe you left it at the party?
我想不可能
I don't think so.
我大概弄丟了  可以記在我帳上嗎?
I must have lost it. Could you put it on the bill, please?
沒問題
Sure.
好了
Here we are.
租金一百五  還有你說的兩百塊...
That was 150 for the rental, 200 you said for my trouble...
面具二十五塊  不好意思...
25 for the mask. Sorry...
一共是三百七十五塊
Three hundred seventy-five.
親愛的?
Yes, dear?
過來
Come, come.
跟哈福醫生打個招呼吧?
Would you like to say hello to Dr. Harford?
- 你好  - 妳好
- Hello. - Hello.
謝謝你  米里區先生  我會再跟你聯絡  再見
Thank you, Mr. Milich. I'll call you soon. Bye-bye.
再見  兩位
Goodbye, gentlemen.
- 聖誕快樂  新年快樂  - 聖誕快樂  新年快樂
- Merry Christmas and happy New Year! - And you too.
哈福醫生...
Well, Dr. Harford...
這是你的收據
here is your receipt.
我現在撕毀你的押金欠條...
I'm tearing up your deposits...
謝謝惠顧
and thanks for the business.
米里區先生  昨晚...
Mr. Milich, last night...
你本來要叫警察的
you were going to call the police.
情況有變  我們達成協議
Well, things change. We have come to another arrangement.
還有  好醫生  如果你需要任何東西...
And by the way, if the good doctor should ever want anything again...
任何東西...
anything at all...
不一定是戲服
it needn't be a costume.
請進
Come in.
- 鮪魚沙拉跟黑咖啡  - 謝謝
- Tuna salad and black coffee. - Thanks.
我下午排了很多病人嗎?
Listen, how's my aternoon looking?
只有兩點半的亞凱利太太  跟四點的科明斯基太太
I think it's just Mrs. Akerly at 2:30 and Mrs. Kominski at 4.
我臨時有事  沒辦法看她們
Well, something's come up, and I'm not gonna be able to see them.
請米勒醫生替我的班  不行的話  幫我致歉
Please ask Dr. Miller if he can fit them in. Otherwise, just apologize...
- 並改時間  - 沒問題
- and make new appointments. - Sure.
還有請幫我呼叫車庫  請他們在半小時內把車開過來
And please call the garage and have them get my car out in half an hour.
- 沒問題  - 好
- No problem. - Okay?
（威廉·哈福醫生）
（放棄你的追蹤調查  這是沒有用的...
這些話是給你的第二次警告
為了你好  這已經足夠）
- 嗨  - 嗨  爹地
- Hi. - Hi, Daddy.
妳們好
Hi.
有人打電話找我嗎?
Any calls for me?
桑德斯醫生與夏皮洛太太
Dr. Sanders and Mrs. Shapiro.
嗨  親愛的
Hey, gang.
- 嗨  爹地  - 嗨
- Hi, Daddy. - Hey.
你看  我全都算對了
Look, I got all these right.
- 妳全都算對啦?  - 是呀
- You got all of those right? - Yeah.
- 每一題嗎?  - 嗯
- Every single one of them? - Mm-hmm.
真棒
That's good.
你餓了嗎?
You hungry?
有點
Sort of.
七點吃飯  好嗎?
Wanna eat at 7?
七點?  不能再早一點嗎?
Seven? Listen, can we make that earlier?
我辦公室還有事
I have some appointments at the office.
你晚上還要出診?
You have to go out again tonight?
恐怕是
I'm afraid so.
爹地  我聖誕節禮物可以要一隻小狗嗎?
Daddy, am I gonna get a puppy for Christmas?
我們再考慮看看  好嗎?
We'll see about that, okay?
他可以當看門狗...
He could be a watchdog...
再看看
We'll see.
來吧  寶貝  把這題做完
Come on, baby, let's finish this off.
好吧  這是喬  他有兩塊半
All right, we have Joe. And Joe has $2.50.
麥克有一塊錢又七十五分
And Mike has $1.75.
喬比麥克多多少錢?
Joe has how much more money than Mike?
七十五分?
$0.75?
所以我們應該用減法還是加法?
So is it gonna be a subtraction or an addition?
"多多少"表示我們應該要用減法
"How much more" means that it would be a subtraction.
因為妳要拿走  對
Yeah, because you're gonna be taking... Right.
我們身邊都是人
And there were all these other people around us.
上百個人  到處都是
Hundreds of them, everywhere.
大家都在亂搞
Everyone was fucking.
我...  我也在搞其他男人
And then I... I was fucking other men.
好多...
So many...
我不知道我跟多少人搞過
I don't know how many I was with.
喂?
Hello.
Hello?
喂?
零錢留著  聖誕快樂
Keep the change. Merry Christmas.
- 誰啊?  - 多米諾?
- What is it? - Domino?
她不在
No, she's not in.
妳想她很快就會回來嗎?
Are you expecting her back soon?
我不認為
No, I'm not.
好吧
Okay.
我有東西要給她  可以交給妳嗎?
I have something for her. Can I leave this with you?
等一下
Just a minute.
你的大名是...?
Can I say who it's from?
就跟她說我是...
Well, just tell her it's from...
比爾
Bill.
- 你是比爾?  - 對
- You're Bill? - Yes.
比爾?  你是昨晚的醫生?
The Bill? You're the doctor who was here last night?
我想沒錯
Well, I suppose I am.
多米諾說你對她很好
Domino said how nice you were to her.
是嗎?
Did she?
進來坐一下吧?
Why don't you come in for a second?
好啊
Sure.
我是莎莉
I'm Sally.
- 妳好  莎莉  - 你好
- Hello, Sally. - Hi.
妳知道多米諾何時回來嗎?
So do you have any idea when you expect Domino back?
不
No.
不知道
I have no idea.
- 妳不知道?  - 對
- You have no idea? - No.
說實話  我想她不會回來了
To be perfectly honest, she may not even be coming back.
她不會回來了?
She may not even be coming back?
嗯  我...
Well...
我...
I...
妳...?
You...?
我想有些事我得告訴你
I think there's something that I should tell you.
- 是嗎?  - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
不過我不知道...
But I just don't know. I don't know.
妳不知道?  那是什麼?
You don't know? Well, what is it?
我不知道我該不該告訴你
I don't know whether to tell you this.
先坐下來吧
Why don't you have a seat?
我們先坐下來
Let's sit down.
- 我不知道該怎麼說  - 妳不知道該怎麼說?
- I don't quite know how to say this. - You don't quite know how?
如果你昨晚跟多米諾在一起...
Well, considering that you were with Domino last night...
我想你有權知道...
I think it would be only fair to you to let you know...
她今天早上接到了血液檢查的結果...
that she got the results of a blood test this morning...
是HIV陽性（愛滋病）
and it was HIV-positive.
- HIV陽性?  - 對
- HIV-positive? - Yeah.
我感到非常遺憾
I am very, very sorry to hear that.
是啊
Yeah.
那是很大的打擊
I mean, it's absolutely devastating.
你要喝點什麼嗎?
Listen, can I offer you anything?
咖啡還是...?
A cup of coffee maybe?
不了  謝謝妳
No, thank you.
我想...
I think...
也許我該走了
maybe I'd better be going.
好的
Okay.
- 計程車  - 下班了
- Taxi! - Off duty.
給我一杯卡布奇諾  謝謝
I'll just have a cappuccino, please.
我會拿過去給你
I'll bring it over to you.
謝謝
Thank you.
（幸運存活下來）
（前選美皇后在旅館用藥過量）
（亞嫚達·科倫  前紐約小姐  因過量服用毒品
在旅館房間内昏迷  今早被送往急救中心）
（急救中心）
（詢問處）
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
我是哈福醫生
I'm Dr. Harford.
我的一個病人今天早上被送來這兒  亞嫚達·科倫
One of my patients was admitted this morning. Miss Amanda Curran.
可以告訴我她的房間號碼嗎?
Could you please give me her room number?
當然  醫生  她的名字是?
Certainly, doctor. Her name again?
科倫  亞嫚達·科倫
Curran. Amanda Curran.
CURRAN?
C-U-R-R-A-N?
是的
Yes.
亞嫚達·科倫小姐?
Miss Amanda Curran?
沒錯
That's right.
我很抱歉  醫生  科倫小姐今天下午過世了
I'm sorry, doctor. Miss Curran died this afternoon.
她今天下午死的?
She died this afternoon?
對  三點四十五分
Yes, at 3:45 p.m.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
因為這會賠上我的生命...
Because it could cost me my life...
可能還有你的
and possibly yours.
喂?
Hello.
是的  我是哈福醫生
Yes, this is Dr. Harford.
今天晚上?
Tonight?
不  沒關係
No, no, no, that's okay.
請告訴他  我二十分鐘後到  好嗎?
Please tell him I'll be there in about 20 minutes. Okay?
請進
Come in.
比爾  感謝你過來  抱歉把你拖來這兒
Bill, I appreciate you coming. Sorry to drag you out here.
- 讓我拿你的外套  - 反正我人已經在外面了  謝謝
- Let me have your coat. - I was out anyway. Thank you.
要來喝一杯嗎?
How about a drink?
- 你也喝嗎?  - 當然
- Are you having one? - Sure.
- 好吧  - 你要喝什麼酒?
- Okay. - What would you like?
- 喝一點蘇格蘭威士忌就好  - 好的
- Just a little scotch. - Good.
- 你喜歡怎麼喝?  不摻水?  - 是的
- How do you take it? Neat? - Please.
前晚的派對真棒
That was a terrific party the other night.
- 艾莉絲跟我都很盡興  - 很好  很好
- Alice and I had a wonderful time. - Well, good. Good.
很高興看到你們兩個
It was great seeing you both.
- 乾杯  - 乾杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
你在玩嗎?
Were you playing?
不  只是隨便打打幾顆球
No, I was just knocking a few balls around.
- 很好的蘇格蘭威士忌  - 存了二十五年
- Beautiful scotch. - That's a 25-year-old.
- 我送你一箱  - 不了  謝謝
- I'll send you over a case. - No, please.
- 為什麼不?  - 不用了
- Why not? - No.
要不要玩?
You feel like playing?
不  謝謝  你繼續玩  我看就好
No, thanks. You go ahead, I'll watch.
我只是...
I was just...
聽著...
Listen...
比爾...
Bill...
我請你來的原因是...
The reason I asked you to come over is...
我有話要跟你說
I need to talk to you about something.
沒問題
Sure.
有點尷尬
It's a little bit awkward.
我必須坦白說
And I have to be completely frank.
你有什麼樣的問題嗎?
What kind of problem are you having?
不是健康問題
It isn't a medical problem.
實際上...
Actually...
跟你有關
it concerns you.
比爾...
Bill...
我知道昨晚發生了什麼事
I know what happened last night.
我也知道之後發生了什麼事
And I know what's been going on since then.
我想你大概...
And I think you just might...
對某些事有些誤解
have the wrong idea about one or two things.
很抱歉  維克特  我...
I'm sorry, Victor, I...
我搞不懂你到底在說什麼?
What in the hell are you talking about?
拜託  比爾  別裝了
Please, Bill, no games.
我也在那兒
I was there.
在那房子裡
At the house.
我目睹了整個過程
I saw everything that went on.
比爾...
Bill...
你以為你在搞什麼鬼啊?
What the hell did you think you were doing?
我根本...
I couldn't...
我根本無法想像...
I couldn't even begin to imagine...
你是怎麼知道這回事...
how you'd even heard about it...
更不要說  你是怎麼通過大門的
let alone got yourself through the door.
然後我想起  你曾跟那該死的鋼琴手聊天...
Then I remembered seeing you with that prick piano player...
叫尼克什麼的  管他叫啥鬼名  在我家的派對上
Nick whatever the fuck his name was, at my party.
之後就不難推測了
And it didn't take much to figure out the rest.
那不是尼克的錯
It wasn't Nick's fault.
那是我的錯
It was mine.
那當然是尼克的錯
Of course it was Nick's fault.
如果他沒跟你提起  這一切都不會發生了
If he hadn't mentioned it to you, none of this would've happened.
我把那雜種推薦給這些人...
I recommended that cocksucker to those people...
他卻讓我顏面盡失
and he's made me look like a complete asshole.
維克特...
Victor...
我能說什麼?
What can I say?
我...
I had...
完全...
absolutely...
沒想到你會被捲入這件事
no idea you were involved in any way.
我知道你沒想到  比爾
I know you didn't, Bill.
不過我也知道...
But I also know that you...
你今早去了尼克的旅館...
You went to Nick's hotel this morning...
還跟門房打探消息
and talked to the desk clerk.
你怎麼知道?
How do you know that?
因為我派人跟蹤你
Because I had you followed.
你派人跟蹤我?
You had me followed?
好吧  我很抱歉
Okay, okay, I'm sorry.
好嗎?  我是該向你道歉
All right? I owe you an apology.
不過那是為你好  相信我
This was for your own good, believe me.
我知道門房對你說了什麼  不過他沒告訴你...
I know what the desk clerk told you. But what he didn't tell you is...
他們只是把尼克架上飛機送回西雅圖
all they did was put Nick on a plane to Seattle.
現在他大概已經回到家裡...
By now he's probably back with his family...
在操尼克太太了
you know, banging Mrs. Nick.
門房說他臉上有淤青
The clerk said he had a bruise on his face.
好吧  他臉上是有淤青
Okay, he had a bruise on his face.
他應得的懲罰比那嚴重多了
That's a hell of a lot less than he deserves.
比爾  我想你不知道你昨晚惹上的麻煩有多大
Listen, Bill, I don't think you realize what kind of trouble you were in last night.
你以為這些人是誰?
Who do you think those people were?
他們可不是一般人
Those were not just ordinary people there.
如果我說出他們的名字...  可我不會告訴你的...
If I told you their names-- I'm not gonna tell you their names...
不過如果我說了  你晚上大概睡不著覺
but if I did, I don't think you'd sleep so well.
是第二道暗語嗎?
Was it the second password?
那是洩漏我身分的原因嗎?
Is that what gave me away?
是的  你總算懂了
Yes, finally.
但不是因為你不知道
But not because you didn't know it.
而是因為根本沒有第二道暗語
It's because there was no second password.
況且這些人是坐禮車來的  而你是搭計程車來的...
Of course it didn't help a whole lot that those people arrive in limos...
那也太明顯了一點
and you showed up in a taxi.
加上他們又在你外套裡找到戲服租借的收據...
Or that they found the receipt from the rental house in your coat...
馬上就知道你是誰了
made out to you-know-who.
那裡...
There was a...
那裡有個女人...
There was a woman there...
她...
who...
曾經想要警告我
tried to warn me.
我知道
I know.
你知道她是誰嗎?
Do you know who she was?
知道
Yes.
她是個...
She was...
她是個妓女
She was a hooker.
抱歉  不過...
Sorry, but...
她真的就是個妓女
that's what she was.
妓女
A hooker.
比爾...
Bill...
假設說...
suppose I told you...
當時發生的一切...
that everything that happened to you there...
威脅  女孩的警告...
the threats, the girl's warnings...
她最後一刻的發言...
her last-minute intervention...
假設我告訴你  那一切...
suppose I said that all of that...
都是設計好的
was staged.
只是一場戲
That it was a kind of charade.
那都是假的
That it was fake.
假的?
Fake?
是的  假的
Yes. Fake.
他們為什麼要那麼做?
Why would they do that?
為什麼?
Why?
簡單地說...
In plain words...
就是要把你嚇得屁滾尿流
to scare the living shit out of you.
讓你不敢再提起你去過哪兒...
To keep you quiet about where you'd been...
還有你看到過什麼
and what you'd seen.
你看過這個了嗎?
Have you seen this?
（前選美皇后在旅館用藥過量）
知道  我看過了
Yes, I have.
我在太平間看到她屍體了
I saw her body in the morgue.
她是...
Was she...
她是在派對上的那個女人嗎?
Was she the woman at the party?
是的
Yes.
她是的
She was.
維克特...
Victor...
躺在太平間的屍體...
the woman lying dead in the morgue...
就是派對上的那個女人
was the woman at the party?
對
Yes.
維克特  也許我搞不清楚
Well, Victor, maybe I'm missing something here.
你說這是假的  一場戲
You called it a fake, a charade.
那這是他媽的哪一種戲...
Do you mind telling me what kind of fucking charade...
會有人在戲裡真的死掉?
ends with somebody turning up dead?
好吧  比爾  我就直接了當說  好嗎?
Okay, Bill, let's cut the bullshit. All right?
你在過去二十四小時內  幹了一堆超過你本分的事
You've been way out of your depth for the last 24 hours.
你想知道這是什麼戲嗎?  我就告訴你這是什麼戲
You wanna know what kind of charade? I'll tell you exactly what kind.
這齣戲從"讓我來"的假犧牲開始...
That whole play-acted, "take me" phony sacrifice...
你的亂來與她真正的死因根本毫無關係
that you've been jerking off with had nothing to do with her real death.
你走了之後  在她身上發生的事  之前也曾發生過
Nothing happened after you left that hadn't happened to her before.
她已經心智不正常了  就這樣
She got her brains fucked out. Period.
當他們帶她回家後  她還很好...
When they took her home, she was just fine...
剩下的都在報紙上了
and the rest is in the paper.
她是個藥頭  嗑藥致死  沒什麼可疑的
She was a junkie. She OD'd. There was nothing suspicious.
她的門從內反鎖  警方高興  案子也結了
Her door was locked from the inside. The police are happy. End of story.
她的死是早晚的事
Come on. It was always gonna be just a matter of time with her.
記得吧  你自己也對她說過
Remember, you told her so yourself.
那個在我房間裡嗑藥過量的波霸美女?
You remember, the one with the great tits who OD'd in my bathroom?
聽著  比爾  沒有誰殺誰
Listen, Bill, nobody killed anybody.
有人死了  這種事常有的
Someone died. It happens all the time.
不過我們還是繼續過活
But life goes on.
總是這樣...
It always does...
直到我們死去
until it doesn't.
不過你已經知道了  對吧?
But you know that, don't you?
我會把一切都告訴妳
I'll tell you everything.
海蓮娜快起床了
Helena's gonna be up soon.
她一直...
She's...
她等著我們帶她去買聖誕節禮物
She's expecting us to take her Christmas shopping today.
不錯
That's nice.
我可以把莎賓娜玩偶放在裡面
I could put Sabrina in here.
真漂亮
It's really pretty.
很傳統
It's old-fashioned.
好大啊
He's big.
我希望聖誕老公公今年會給我這個
I hope Santa Claus gets me one of these for Christmas.
真的嗎?
You do?
那妳就得等著瞧囉
Well, you're gonna have to wait and see.
艾莉絲...
Alice.
妳覺得我們該怎麼辦?
What do you think we should do?
我覺得我們該怎麼辦?
What do I think we should do?
看  媽咪
Look, Mommy!
嗨
Hey.
我的想法嗎?  我不知道
What do I think? I don't know.
也許...
I mean, maybe...
嗨
Hey.
我想...
Maybe I think...
我們應該感到慶幸
we should be grateful.
慶幸...
Grateful...
我們能夠捱過這些...
that we've managed to survive through all of our...
冒險...
adventures...
不論是真的冒險...
whether they were real...
還是只是一場夢
or only a dream.
妳確定嗎?
Are you sure of that?
我確定嗎?
Am I sure?
只能...
Only...
我只能確定...
Only as sure as I am...
一晚的真實...
that the reality of one night...
甚至是一輩子的真實...
let alone that of a whole lifetime...
也不可能是全部的真相
can ever be the whole truth.
夢也不會...
And no dream is ever...
只是一場夢
just a dream.
最重要的是...
The important thing is...
我們現在醒了...
we're awake now...
希望...
and hopefully...
這能持續好長一段時間
for a long time to come.
永遠
Forever.
永遠?
Forever?
永遠
Forever.
別用那個字眼  好嗎?
Let's not use that word. You know?
它让我感到害怕
It frightens me.
不過我真的愛你...
But I do love you...
而且你知道...
and you know...
有件事更重要...
there is something very important...
我們必須馬上進行
that we need to do as soon as possible.
是什麼?
What's that?
上床做愛
Fuck.
製片兼導演: 史丹利·庫柏力克
編劇: 史丹利·庫柏力克
菲得理克·拉法埃爾
改編自小說"夢幻記"
原著作者: 亞瑟·史尼茲勒
[ MANDARIN -  R3 ]